I don't like people very much. I'm just not a very nice person.
我不太愛跟人打交道 也不太好相處
The world is broken.
世風日下
You shouldn't watch scary movies close to bedtime.
你不該睡覺前看恐怖電影
We may dislike Mr Foyle.We do not have to like him to defend him.
我們也許并不喜歡Foyle先生 但為他辯護并不需要喜歡他
I don't do things for exposure.
我做事不是為了曝光率 Maggie
- Why then? - Everyone deserves a defence.
- 那是為了什么 - 每個人都享有辯護的權利
Given the press this case has generated, Mr Foyle cannot be given a fair trial.
考慮到本案已有的輿論傾向 Foyle無法得到公正的審判
I have no alternative but to discharge the jury
我別無他法 只能解散陪審團
and release the defendant.
釋放被告
Will, good man. Thank you, my friend.
Will 你真是好人 謝謝 朋友
Pleasure. Take care.
客氣 保重
We'll see you up there. But hurry up, I want to show you something.
我們准備出發了 盡快哦 我有東西給你看
Kate?! Jamie!
Kate? Jamie
Dad! Jamie!
- 爸爸 - Jamie!
You're defending him.
你擔任他的辯護律師
- Everyone deserves a defence. - That's right.
- 每個人都享有辯護的權利 - 是的 Maggie
That's right.
說的是
Sync:FRS@Õº“¡¿≠ÕØ“•
-=風軟FRM字幕組=- 翻譯: mgydz 雨瀟 沒腦聰 米大寶 校對: 雨瀟 時間軸: 圖伊拉童謠
The Escape Artist S01E02
脫罪大師 第一季 第二集
www.1000fr.net presents
-==http://www.1000fr.net==- 謦靈風軟影視論壇榮譽出品 本字幕僅供學習交流，嚴禁用于商業用途
Mum! Mum! Dad!
媽媽 媽媽 爸爸
Help! Dad! Dad! No! DAD!!
救命 爸爸 不要 爸爸
- Dad!! No! - All right... All right...
- 爸爸 不要啊 - 沒事 沒事的
It's all right, all right. It's OK.
沒事 別緊張 沒事的
It's all right, it's all right. Shh. Ssshhhh...
沒事 沒事了
Harris? Trevor Harris. Anyone?
Harris? Trevor Harris 人呢
Plea and case management on Will's case.
來談談Will一案的抗辯及排期管理
Whole thing just got moved up.
整個程序提前了
- We'll have to change the dates. - Good.
- 我們得改日程 - 好啊
No, not good at all.
好什么好
We need all the bloody time we can get.
時間緊得很啊
We're absolutely sure Will's son didn't see anything.
Will的兒子肯定什么也沒看到
It's just if we had two witness statements. I mean,
要是有兩段目擊証人陳述
it would take the weight off the DNA.
那DNA的分量就可以減輕
- If it comes in. - This is where we are.
- 如果有的話 - 現在就這情況
This is what we've have to work with. Blood, ID, alibi.
我們只能靠這些 血液 目擊者 不在場証明
And God help us, a following wind.
運氣好算是老天保佑
No, that's what I'm trying to explain to you.
不 我不是這個意思
Look, my wife does not wear aftershave
聽好 我老婆不用須后水
and I am not the least bit interested in Peter Rabbit collectibles.
我對彼得兔周邊一點都沒興趣
So if you want me to join the dots for you, someone has stolen my wife's identity.
綜上所述就是 有人假冒了我老婆
Yeah, well, that's not going to happen, is it?
那不可能的吧
Well, you can't talk to her.
你沒法找她說
Yeah, I already identified her.
嗯 我確認過她身份了
I walked into the mortuary and kissed her face.
我去了停尸間親過她
Yeah.
去你媽的
Did I scare you?
我嚇到你了嗎
I'm sorry.
對不起
I wish things could be different, but they're not.
我希望這不是真的 可惜就是
Look, if you ever want to tell me something, anything,
如果你有事想告訴我 什么都行
about what happened, I'll be here. OK?
說說當時的情況 盡管來找我 好嗎
Just come right out and say it.
過來找我說就好
I'll be listening.
我洗耳恭聽
Yeah?
好不好
When it rains, what happens to all the little animals?
下雨了小動物會怎么樣
- Do they drown, do you think? - Mr Foyle.
- 你說它們會淹死嗎 - Foyle先生
I used to love it when it rained.
我從前好愛下雨天
But now I get so sad when it's wet out cos all I can think about is
如今外面濕答答的我就難受 因為我總想著啊
all these little bodies clawing and squeaking at the earth and the mud
小動物在陸地泥潭水塘中掙扎尖叫
and the water and drowning in the dark.
默默地淹死
It's a shame the plants have to drink. I know they do,
植物要喝水真遺憾 雖然不喝不行
but it's a shame. I get so sad when it's wet.
但真遺憾啊 濕答答的可難受了
Especially after the summer we had.
尤其大夏天過后
Mr Foyle, we need to be sure that you understand your plea.
Foyle先生 我們得確定你清楚辯詞
Is there any evidence that puts me at the cottage?
有証據表明我去過度假屋嗎
You were charged on the basis of one eyewitness identification.
你被起訴是因為有目擊者指認
- One. - Yes, one.
- 就一個 - 對 一個
- The son hasn't made a statement. - Not yet.
- 那小孩還沒做陳述 - 暫時沒有
Yet.
暫時
You think he saw something?
你覺得他有看到什么嗎
There's only one witness. That's what we're dealing with.
只有一位目擊者 情況就是這樣
What's that?
這什么
Tea.
茶
- What kind of tea? - My tea.
- 什么茶 - 我的茶
We also need to talk about your alibi, Ms Morris.
還得說說不在場証明 Morris女士
We go into considerable detail in our defence statement about our whereabouts that evening
抗辯中會詳細提及當晚的去向
and we are confident she will support this.
我們確信Morris女士能証明這點
Then why do we need to discuss this?
那還討論個什么啊
Because we need to discuss this.
必須討論
Mr Burton is the only witness in this whole case.
本案唯一目擊者是Burton先生
So he can't act for himself.
因此他無法為自己辯護
You're well-versed in criminal procedure.
你很了解刑事訴訟
I did a law course.
我修過法律課程
- Oh, really, where was that? - Cambridge.
- 是嘛 哪兒學的 - 劍橋
Anglia Polytechnic University.
英吉利理工大學
We probably cycled past one another on Silver Street.
指不定咱在Silver街有擦肩而過呢
- It's a small world. - Indeed.
- 世界真小 - 小得很
Yes, you're right, Mr Burton will not be in court.
你說對了 Burton先生不會上庭
As he's a witness, he cannot act for the Crown in any way.
身為目擊者 他不能當檢方律師
It's just that, you know, he kept beating you, is all.
那什么 他一直贏你
He's not allowed to be there.
法庭不允許他去
So he just has to watch.
那他只好旁觀了
I suppose so.
是的
Besides, it was very dark.
話說 當時真暗啊
Shame about all those animals,
小動物們真可憐
isn't it?
對吧
You have qualms.
你很不安
I beg your pardon?
什么
It's your first big defence. You're working late.
第一次為要案當辯護律師 你要熬夜備戰
- You have qualms. - He lost his wife.
- 你很不安 - 他老婆沒了
If the tables were turned, he would not hesitate.
如果換成他 他會毫不猶豫
This is how it works.
這是律師本職
I just know that if I was Will...
我知道如果我是Will...
Ah. But you're not him, are you?
可你不是他啊
Not yet, anyway.
反正暫時不是
All right?
怎么了
I've probably only got about five minutes. It's a bit of a crazy morning.
我只有五分鐘 早上忙死了
How's it looking?
情況如何
Every time I pass the conference room there's a huge queue of people knocking on the door.
每次路過會議室都有一堆人敲門
Everyone wants to help, mate.
大家都想幫忙 兄弟
- Who's leading? - Mr Mayfield.
- 誰是主控 - Mayfield先生
Mr Harris is his junior.
Harris先生給他當副手
Everyone else was busy.
其他人都很忙
Any idea what they are running with?
知道具體情況嗎
You don't have to say a thing if you don't want to.
不想說別勉強
Forensics found a size 12 boot print in the garden.
鑒証科在院子里找到46碼的鞋印
But all Foyle's footwear is a size nine. No match on the tread.
但Foyle穿43碼 鞋印也不吻合
So as far as I can tell they are all waiting for the forensics' report.
據我所知大家都在等鑒証科報告
The crime scene blood. Plus, your ID of him.
案發現場的血跡 還有你對他的指認
- And? - I think that's it.
- 還有呢 - 沒有了
What about his alibi?
他的不在場証明呢
His neighbour said she had dinner with him.
他鄰居說有跟他一起吃晚飯
They are looking into possible angles.
大家在試著從不同角度著手
- What's this woman's name? - Eileen Morris.
- 這女的叫什么 - Eileen Morris
Say that again.
你說什么
Eileen Morris, right?
Eileen Morris是吧
Did a little rooting around in the old case file.
我翻了翻舊案
This is all I could come up with.
只找到這個
He's a bird fancier, if you remember.
你還有印象嗎 他愛鳥如命
See who's presenting him with that trophy?
你看誰給他頒獎呢
"Parish Council Events Committee Co-Chair Eileen Morris."
"教區活動事務委員會 聯合主席Eileen Morris"
That's all I've got for you I'm afraid.
我只查到這些了
There was something else. I'm sure I've seen her name somewhere else.
不止 我肯定在別處見過這名字
Thanks, Bob.
謝了 Bob
You're welcome.
不客氣
Foyle's alibi might not be as solid as they're making out.
Foyle的不在場証明 也許沒他們說的這么牢固
How do you know that?
你怎么曉得的
Doesn't seem fair.
不公平啊
Biggest legal brain in the building,
明明是樓里最頂尖的律師
can't even talk to them about your own bloody case.
卻不能對自己的案子發表意見
No, I can't.
的確不行
Not directly.
不能明著來
It's not like I am defending him anymore, is it?
我不再為他辯護了 對吧
Do you have any idea where the Sandra Mullins case files are?
知道Sandra Mullins的卷宗在哪嗎
I think so, yeah. Big box. Stubbed my toe on it last week.
知道 那個大盒子 我上周還踩到過
Do you think it might be near my office?
你說它離我辦公室近不近?
I think it could be.
可以近啊
Mr Harris!
Harris先生
Did you see the Collingwood arson brief? The private one?
Collingwood縱火案卷宗你見過嗎 保密的那個
Yes, I caught sight of it as it flew past me at high velocity
嗯 丟給御用大律師的時候
on its way to one of the silks.
我有見過一眼
Why don't you take a page out of Tara's book?
你怎么不學學Tara呢
My nose is brown enough already, thank you.
謝了 我哪還有空拍馬屁
She does what she has to. Why don't you do that now and then?
她也是做分內事 你怎么就不呢
Because then I'd be like Tara, wouldn't I?
那我就跟Tara沒差了 不是嗎
You heading over?
你有急事?
Foyle's making his plea.
Foyle要做抗辯陳述了
How's it looking, do you think?
你覺得情況怎么樣
No sign of DNA at the scene,
現場沒留下DNA
single eyewitness, recognition under duress. Not a lot of wiggle room.
只有一個目擊者被迫指認 沒什么回旋余地
Will's boy was there - but if he had seen something, well,
Will的兒子也在場 如果他看到什么
he would have said something, wouldn't he?
早就該說了不是嗎
Mr Harris.
Harris先生
- Don't.Well,stop. - No, I've been thinking.
- 別說 打住 - 不行 我憋很久了
I mean it.
我說真的
Time to go.
該上庭了
Hi, Jamie, welcome back.
嗨 Jamie 歡迎回來
- Are you OK? - See you.
- 你還好吧 - 回見
- Are you all right? - All right.
- 你沒事吧 - 沒事
Liam Michael Foyle, you are charged on this indictment with one count of murder.
Liam Michael Foyle 你被指控一項謀殺罪名
- How do you plead? - Not guilty.
- 你如何抗辯 - 本人無罪
My Lord, given the lack of evidence at this time we are serving a bail application notice.
法官大人 考慮到証據不足 我方正在申請保釋
- First I've heard of it. - It was served in good time.
- 我方并未聽說 - 已經適時申請了
- I thought I gave it to you. - Well, I read it.
- 我給你看過了啊 - 嗯 我讀過了
Bail granted, subject to conditions as per application.
經由審批 被告獲准保釋
Thank you. Also, I've spoken to the List Officer who's informed me
謝謝 法官大人 今早我與排期員確認過
a slot is available for a week-long case on the 31st.
本月31號能安排開審 為期一周的案件
- Very well. - Wait.
- 很好 - 稍等
That's only a few weeks away. It hardly gives us any time to prepare the evidence?
只有几周的時間 我們几乎沒有什么時間准備証據
What evidence?
什么証據
Mr Foyle, you may leave the dock.
Foyle先生 你可以離開被告席了
All rise.
全體起立
Never said thank you. Oh, you're welcome.
- 還沒感謝過你呢 - 沒什么
See you soon.
回見
Yes.
好的
You're in a lot of trouble.
你的麻煩大了
I made you some crumble.
我給你做了些奶酥
I must have left my cage open cos a little birdie just bailed me out.
我一定是忘了關籠子 有只小小鳥把我保釋出來了
You shouldn't have done that, Eileen, really.
你不該這樣的Eileen 真的
It takes half an hour.
只花了半個小時
That's not what I am talking about.
我說的不是這個
Oh, please. I was happy to pay.
別這樣 我樂意付錢
Welcome home.
歡迎回家
Apple or plum?
蘋果餡的還是李子餡的
Rhubarb. It's in the fridge at the parish council,
大黃餡的 在教區委員會的冰箱里
waiting for you.
等著你呢
It won't be there too long, I promise.
我保証它不會久等的
- Lots to be getting on with. - Oh, sure.
- 還有很多要忙的 - 沒錯
- I fed them every day, just like you asked. - Good.
- 我照你的囑咐每天都喂它們 - 很好
Everybody's hungry.
大伙都餓了
All right, let's run it again, shall we?
好了 我們再過一遍 好嗎
Post mortem indicates Kate was strangled before he cut into her.
尸檢表明在他划破她喉嚨前 Kate是被勒住的
- The knife entered... - Any update on the footprints?
- 刀划過... - 腳印有什么新的發現嗎
Locus is littered with them, all the wrong size.
現場布滿腳印 碼數全對不上
After that, the blade passed through the trachea...
之后 刀鋒划過氣管
You don't "pass through" the trachea.
不是"划過"氣管
It's a sawing motion. The core strength of a fast bowler.
是用力割的 手法快而有力
- Gavin! - One hell of a blood spatter.
- Gavin - 血跡濺了一地
Will's here.
Will來了
- How the hell did this happen? - The usual way.
- 他怎么來這了 - 跟往常一樣唄
What? He came in the front door.
沒錯啊 他從正門進來的
Close the bloody folder, will you?
把該死的文件夾合上好嗎
There's pictures of his wife!
那是他妻子的照片
- Call ahead if you're going to just turn up. - I work here, too.
- 你再這么突然過來要提前說一聲 - 我也是這的員工
Everyone's behind you, but get caught trying to influence the case,
所有人都支持你 但如果被發現企圖干擾案件
you're jeopardising the enterprise.
你就會危害到事務所
You're the only witness. So hands off.
你是唯一的目擊証人 別碰這個案子
Protocol doesn't just need to be followed,
協議不只是要遵守
it needs to be seen to be followed.
還不能讓人抓到把柄
I know. I actually studied law.??
我明白 我大學學的就是法律
??We'd prefer it if you didn't even come into chambers.
老實說 我們寧愿你連剛才都沒進去過
???If I have to stay home one more day, I swear I'm going to kill somebody.
如果我在家再呆多一天 我發誓我絕對會要殺人
I need to work. Please?
我需要工作 拜托了
It was today, wasn't it? The plea?
抗辯在今天 對嗎
They didn't call you?
他們沒打電話給你嗎
They should've called you.
他們該打給你的
- Talk to me! - Not guilty.
- 說話啊 - 無罪
Remanded where? The Scrubs?
拘留在哪? Scrubs?
Actually he got bail.
實際上他被保釋了
Already in custody, low risk of absconding.
已經被拘留過 潛逃的風險低
It's conditional.
是有條件的
- When was this? - This morning.
- 什么時候的事 - 今早
You should really be doing this through the... proper channels.
你真的應該通過法律渠道來處理這事
- Lend us chewing gum. - Yeah.
- 給我們賒了口香糖 - 是啊
- Did you hear about Dr Foster?
- 你聽說Foster博士的事了嗎 - 嗯
Dr Foster.
Foster博士
It's Will Burton, Jamie's Dad. Tell him I'll be there to pick him up?
我是Will Burton Jamie的爸爸 能告訴他我會去接他嗎
"He left with Alfie, they said they were getting the bus together."
他和Alfie走了 他們說要一塊兒搭公車
All right, thanks.
好的 謝謝
- Connor, have you seen Jamie?OK. - No.No, I haven't.
- Connor 你見到Jamie了嗎 - 沒 沒看到
Mum, anything?
媽 有消息嗎
Is he here? They said he'd already left.
他在嗎 他們說他已經走了
Why didn't you call me?!
為什么不打電話給我
Hi, Pat, is Jamie there?
嗨 Pat Jamie在嗎
- I was wondering if he came home with Alfie? - Have you tried the library?
- 我想知道他是不是和Alfie一起回家的 - 你找過圖書館嗎
- Is that a new phone? - I got it recently.
- 這是新手機嗎 - 我新得的
Listen to this.
聽這個
Yeah, I heard it on the radio yesterday.
我昨天在廣播里聽到了
Ah, it's my stop. See you. See you at school.
我到了 再見 學校見
Did he get off at Alfie's stop?
他在Alfie那站下車了嗎
OK. All right.
好的 謝謝
No, don't worry. Don't worry. Thanks.
沒事 別擔心 謝謝
That's it, I'm calling the police.
不行 我要報警了
Jamie?!
Jamie
Where have you been?!
你去哪兒了
We went to the shop.
我們去商店了
- Did you talk to anyone? - No.
- 你有和誰說話嗎 - 沒有
Promise me you'll not talk to anyone you don't know, OK?
向我保証你不會和陌生人說話 好嗎
Not on the street, the playground, not anywhere.
別在街上 別在操場 哪兒都別說
I'm picking you up from school from now on. OK?
從今天起我去學校接你 好嗎
Every single day. OK?
每一天 知道嗎
- Dad! - Just give me a minute.
- 爸 - 讓我再抱會兒
- The sea lions of Moscow are horny this time of year. - Up yours.
- 每年這時候都是莫斯科海象的發情期 - 去你的
Oh, relax.
放松點
- Right, come on. Let's go upstairs. - Why?
- 好了來吧 咱們到樓上去 - 為什么
Come on, boy.
來吧 伙計
Come on.
來啊
- Couldn't meet in a park? - It's the best place to hide, in a crowd.
- 為什么就不能在公園見面 - 最佳的藏身之處就是在人群里
- In plain sight. - Plain stupid.
- 不起眼的地方 - 蠢透了
We're just chatting. Two blokes having a chat.
我們不過是在聊天 兩個哥們說說話
What do you want to do?
你想干什么
Let's talk football.
咱們來聊聊足球
I used to love our team. I still love our team.
我之前喜歡我們的球隊 現在也喜歡
D'you know what I think the problem is?
你知道我覺得問題出在哪嗎
We're missing our star striker.
咱們缺少了明星前鋒
No way can he can play. It's against the rules.
他不能上場 這有違規定
- He can hardly score goals from the bench. - He can't even watch the match.
- 他在替補席拿不了分 - 他連比賽都不能看
- He's forbidden from watching the match. - Absolutely.
- 他被禁止觀看比賽了 - 正是
So I am thinking that, from time to time,
所以我就想 也許我能時不時
maybe I could get someone to talk to you about our attacking game.
找人來和你談談我們的進攻戰略
- Danny. - The door's over there if you're feeling uncomfortable. I say a door.
- Danny - 如果你覺得不適的話門就在那 我是說門
- You need a better goalmouth strategy. - Christ, don't do that.
- 你需要一個更好的門前戰略 - 天啊 別這樣
What's the matter?
怎么了
What's the matter? What's the
怎么了 怎么了
- Trevor.What's the matter? - Hi.
- Trevor 怎么了 - 嗨
You do know what it is you're doing, what we're doing, don't you?
你知道你這是在干什么 咱們這是在干什么嗎
- What is it we're doing exactly? - We're talking.
- 我們究竟是在干什么 - 我們在聊天
About football.Here we are, men talking about football.
聊足球 只是在聊足球
Nothing wrong with that.
這有什么不對
Except when footballers talk about football before a match
但是足球運動員比賽前聊足球
they don't lose their jobs. ??
他們可不會丟工作不是嗎
I know this is a big ask.
我知道這是個大忙
I appreciate you must have been hoping that Mayfield would pick someone else,
我知道你一定希望Mayfield能選別人
someone more suited, perhaps, to something like this,
一個也許更適合處理這種案件的人
but the fact is, everyone else was gainfully employed
但事實是 大家手頭都忙著
and, well,I'm just sorry it had to be me.
抱歉 只好讓我來了
You're the hardest-working barrister in the set.
你是事務所里最努力的律師
Well, I...Thank you. All the same,
謝謝 不過
I need to think about it.
我要考慮一下
Foyle had a storage unit.
Foyle之前有個儲藏間
He told us about it during the Sandra Mullins trial.
他在Sandra Mullins那個案的時候告訴我們的
He cleared it out six months before the murder.
他在謀殺發生六個月之前 清空并且停止付費了
It played no further part in the proceedings.
審理過程沒有進一步提及它
Someone took it on after him. Eileen Morris.
在他之后有人接手了 她叫Eileen Morris
If something's not turning up it just might mean you need to look for it somewhere else.
如果案件沒有發現的話 就意味著你要換一個地方找
Probatio vincit praesumptionem.
(拉丁語)証據大于推定
- Thanks for the drink. - You're welcome.That's for you, by the way.
- 謝謝你請的飲料 - 不客氣 以及這是給你的
- What's that? - Colinwood brief. Mr Spencer's off on holiday.
- 這是什么 - Colinwood案的案卷 Spencer先生去度假了
- Where's he going? - I haven't decided yet.
- 他去哪 - 我還沒定下來
I need to ask you something.
我要問你點事
In the cottage, you didn't actually see that man, did you?
你在度假屋里真的沒有 看到那個男人 對嗎
It was dark.
當時很黑
Sorry, I shouldn't have asked.
對不起 我不該問的
- What? - "Am I disturbing you?"
- 怎么了 - 沒打擾你吧
- What do you want, Peter? - "Can you spare an hour tonight?"
- 你想怎么樣 Peter - 你占用你一個鐘頭嗎
- It's late. - "You didn't answer the question."
- 現在很晚了 - 你沒回答問題
- Tonight's a bit difficult. - Difficult for all of us, my dear.
- 今晚有點困難 - 大家都有困難 親愛的
Foyle is our client. He's called a meeting.
Foyle是我們的委托人 他要見個面
"We have a duty to listen."
我們有義務去聽一聽
- "He sounds very interested. -" Yeah.
- 他聽起來很興奮 - 好的
"Says he's remembered something."
說他記起了點東西
I said yes.
我已經同意了
Straight to voicemail.
直接轉語音信箱了
Send a clerk round.
派一個人過去
Where?
去哪
Harrods.
Harrods
His house. To his house.
他家 去他家
We can't do that.
我們不能這樣
I'm not staying here all night.
我才不要一整晚都呆在這
"Hi, it's Kate. I'm not here right now, but leave a message. Bye."
我是Kate 我現在不在 不過可以留言 再見
now, but leave a message. Bye!"
你好我是Kate 我現在不在 請留言 再見
It's all right. No! It's me, it's me, it's me.
別怕 是我 是我 是我
Jesus. You were half a second away from an eye patch.
天啊 再遲點你的眼睛就得受罪了
Foyle murdered Sandra Mullins. You need to know that.
Foyle殺了Sandra Mullins 你得知道這個
You said otherwise in court.
你在法庭上可不是這么說的
I see things differently now.
現在我的看法變了
If you had reservations you should have acted on those.
如果你對他有所懷疑 就早該采取行動的
He claimed his innocence and I spoke for him. I lawyered him out of it, that's all.
他自稱無罪而我為他辯護 我不過是盡職責為他脫罪
But I know he killed her.
但我知道他殺了她
He is a murderer, there is no doubt.
他是個凶手 毫無疑問
We differ on this point.
這點我不能同意
I mean it. You need to be careful.
我是認真的 你萬事小心
You can't stand seeing me do well, can you?
你就是見不得我成功 對吧
This is good for me.
這對我有利
Good for you?
對你有利?
I am truly sorry for what happened to you, but this is a job.
我為你的遭遇感到抱歉 但這是工作
Work is work. That's it.
工作歸工作 僅此而已
Foyle murdered Kate.
Foyle殺了Kate
You let that man in, you are risking everything.
你為這人工作 就等于堵上自己的一切
Don't make the same mistake.
別犯同樣的錯誤
- Goodnight, Will. - I mean it. Don't be alone.
- 晚安 Will - 我是認真的 別單獨行動
Did your... Did your friend find you?
你朋友找到你了嗎
- Friend? - Yeah, he rang your doorbell.
- 朋友? - 是啊 他摁了你的門鈴
What makes you think it was my friend?
你為什么說他是我的朋友
He put your bin bag out.
他把你的垃圾拿走了
She...
她...
- King makes the travel arrangements - - Blood was all Kate's.
- King會做行程安排的 - 現場的血都是Kate的
No DNA match to Foyle whatsoever.
沒有和Foyle匹配的DNA
What does that leave exactly?
現在我們到底有些什么
Will's ID of Foyle in the locus, going for this alibi,
Will關于Foyle在場的口供 駁斥他的不在場証明
and that's it.
就沒了
Does that even get you through the door?
這值得你特意進來說一聲嗎
All the same we need to collate some skeleton arguments on how to beat
同時我們還要整理辯護提綱
a Turnbull Direction should it come to it.
以防Turnbull指導
That's like arguing with a tube train in a tunnel.
根本沒有勝算
I don't see they have much choice.
我們沒有別的選擇
No, well, quite.
是的  沒錯
Yes, thank you for all your help.
多謝你的幫助
We said we'd be there for him.
我們說過會盡力幫他
- Yes, well we will be. - How, exactly?
- 是的 那是當然 - 到底怎么幫
I think we've missed a trick.
我覺得我們都忽略了一點
I've been digging in the old files. There was a storage unit.
我一直在翻閱舊的文檔 有一處儲藏間
Foyle had one before the Sandra Mullins murder.
Foyle在Sandra Mullins謀殺案前租用過
It didn't make it into the evidence because he'd emptied it six months before.
之所以沒有作為証據 是因為半年前他清空了倉庫
It was passed on to somebody else.
轉給了其他人
Want to guess who?
知道是誰嗎
She's his alibi. She cooked him dinner at her home.
是他的不在場証明人 說當時在她家給他做晚飯
OK...
好吧...
- You're sure she was paying for this? - Direct debit ever since.
- 你確定是她一直在付租用費嗎 - 用的借記卡 查到了
If we're drawing a blank on the link to the locus it doesn't mean there isn't one,
如果在現場找不到蛛絲馬跡 不一定真的什么都沒有
it might just mean we're looking in the wrong place.
也許只是我們找錯了地方
Probatio vincit praesumptionem.
証據大于推定原則
Get a call into the OIC for me, will you? We need a warrant in motion.
幫我打個電話給辦案干事 我們需要申請搜查令
In the meantime, let's revisit all we know about Eileen Murray.
同時我們再重新 查一下Eileen Murray這個人
The IOC for you.
接通了
It's like he's finally worked out how to switch on his brain.
看起來他終于開始動腦子工作了
What is it?
什么事
They called me again, about my statement.
他們又打電話問了我証詞
I thought you gave one?
你不是給過了嗎
They asked me to clarify it. Again.
他們想讓我再次確認一下
And what did you say?
你說什么了
Well, I told them the truth.
說實話
I told them all about our evening.
就是那晚我們吃飯的事
Well, there are you, then.
那就好
But why did they need to check up on me like that?
但為什么他們要再檢查一遍呢
I don't know.
我不知道
But there's nothing more to worry about,... is there?
但沒什么好擔心的 不是嗎
No, I suppose there's not.
是 我想也是
You look freezing.
你凍壞了
Why don't you come in for a minute?
進來坐會兒吧
- Oh, I just have to pop home first. - Now, if that's OK.
- 我只是要先回趟家 - 就現在 你方便的話
OK. OK.
好的 方便
You know anything about kettles?
你知道熱水壺怎么弄嗎
Oh, it's switched off at the wall. Oh.
哦 插頭掉下來了
These people, these lawyers,
那些人 那些律師
they don't see you.
他們是不會在意你的
Did you know that?
知道嗎
They don't have an ounce of mercy in them. And I'll be honest, Eileen.
他們沒什么慈悲心 而且說實話 Eileen
They can be very manipulative.
他們非常善于操縱別人
Eileen, I want to protect you as best as I can, I really do,
Eileen 我想盡力保護你 真的
but...I need you to be a little more sure of yourself.
但我希望你自己能更確信一下
- Sure? - Of yourself.
- 確信? - 相信你自己
Yeah, I think I can do that, yes.
我想我可以的
You be you... and I'll be them.
你就做你自己 我來演他們
Miss Morris, can you tell the court where you were on the evening of the 3rd of December?
Morris小姐 你能否告訴法官 12月3日晚上你在哪里嗎
I was at home.
我在家里
And what did you have to eat?
你晚上吃了什么
- Spaghetti carbonara. - Wrong.
- 奶油意面 - 不對
- Er... Con funghi.
- 呃 燴蘑菇
- No, it's not.
- 不是的
- Er... I don't... I don't understand. - Have courage in your conviction.
- 呃 我不是 不是很明白 - 更有勇氣和信念一點
Don't let them rattle you.
別讓他們弄慌了神
What did you have to eat?
你吃了什么
- Spaghetti con... fu... um...I'm all confused now. - Are you, Eileen? Are you confused?
- 意面 蘑 蘑菇 我搞不清楚了 - 是嗎 Eileen 你真的記不清了嗎
Confused doesn't help us.
記不清幫不了我們
Confused makes everything go away.
記不清讓一切都白費了
Am I hurting you?
我弄疼你了嗎
Yes.
是的
Am... I... hurting... you?
我...弄疼...你了...嗎
And what did you make for dinner that night?
那晚你做了什么晚餐
S... Spaghetti Carbonara...
奶油意面
Cup of tea?
想喝茶嗎
Gavin, can I ask your expert opinion on something.
Gavin 我能問你一個專業的意見嗎
Yes, of course.
當然
A barrister can't coach a witness, correct?
出庭律師不能指導証人說辭 對嗎
Gross misconduct. He'd be out in a flash.
嚴重違紀 會立馬被處罰
What about a witness coaching a barrister?
那証人指導律師呢
I have a friend who is displaying a sudden and surprising burst of talent.
我有個朋友 突然之間變得很有才能
I think he's getting help.
我覺得有人在幫他
Well, he's not just risking his own neck.
他不止是拿自己在冒險
He's risking his case, his client, and the reputation of his Chambers.
還是在拿他的案子 他的委托人 以及律所的名聲在冒險
So, for the sake of your chum,
為了你的朋友好
I suggest you find out what's going on.
你最好去弄明白怎么回事
Thank you.
謝謝
Did you need to go in the other one? They're both mine.
你們需要查另外一個嗎 也是我的
- Yes, we will. - Well, it's a bit of a, sorry, a bit of a squeeze.
- 是的 - 這里有點 抱歉 有點擠
Cos this one's mine as well, so...
因為這個也是我的
They found a size 12 boot in the storage unit. It's a strong candidate to match a tread in the locus.
他們在儲藏間里發現了雙46碼的鞋子 和案發現場的腳印一致
Foyle's a size nine. Doesn't stop him wearing a bigger boot.
Foyle穿43碼 不代表他不能穿大號的鞋子
Forget the alibi, focus on the boot. Get her on stand and make the connection.
別管不在場証明了 調查那雙鞋 把她弄到我們這邊 尋找關聯
But if we call her as our witness we can't cross examine her on the alibi, can we?
但如果她作為我方証人 我們就不能給她之前的口供証偽了 是嗎
Her alibi's based on good character. It's a hard sell to undermine her.
她的不在場証明是基于她良好的個人品格 很難從這方面撼動她
Show in court they have an undisclosed connection through the storage unit,  her credibility's undermined.
你在庭上需要從儲藏倉庫証明 他們之間有秘密聯系 才能讓她成為不可信証人
You may not have to do that if you prove this boot was at the scene.
如果能証明這靴子 就是案發現場那雙 你根本就不用費力証明
A big choice. It's bite the bullet time. That's the way you should go.
這需要你忍痛抉擇 到底想走哪條路
Tara's here. Walk away.
Tara在這兒 快走
- Walk away. - Prove the link, undermine her. Double bubble.
- 快走 - 証明聯系 讓她不可信 記住了
Oh, and make sure that warrant was kosher.
哦 要確保搜查令不違規
Trev! Looking a little bit lost there.
Trev 你看起來像迷路了啊
Tara. Hi.
Tara 嗨
- What are you doing here? - Is Danny around?
- 你來這兒干什么 - Danny不在這兒嗎
Why, have you seen him? Huh!
不在 你見到他了?
- How bad? - "She saw Harris. And she may have seen you too."
- 多糟糕 - 她看見Harris了 也許也看見你了
So we're burned. We're done.
所以我們完蛋了
"So what happens now?"
那現在怎么辦
We cross our bloody fingers.
只能求好運了
I'm very sorry.
我很抱歉
I crossed a line.
我過分了
Yes, you did.
是的沒錯
I've been so stressed about everything.
我壓力太大了
I'm sure you are.
我想是的
See you later.
晚上見
It's the first day of trial today.
庭審第一天
They'll be arguing about evidence. Jury's not in yet. You remember the drill.
他們會就証據進行辯論 陪審團還沒介入 你知道會怎么樣的
Probably going to take Jamie up to the cottage this weekend, go through your stuff.
這周末也許會帶Jamie去度假屋 整理一下你的東西
It's time. It might be good for him, you know?
是時候了 也許對他有幫助
You were always better at that sort of stuff than me, but we'll see how it goes.
這種事你總是做得比我好 看看這次吧
That way it's done before I have to take the stand.
在我站上証人席之前 會做好的
Everyone's done what they can. Everyone's been great.
每個人都做了他們能做的 他們都很好
A lot of people really love you.
很多人真的很愛你
We'll do our best, OK?
我們會盡力的 好嗎
I promise.
我保証
Relax.
放松
So they found a boot. Big deal.
他們找到了雙靴子 沒什么了不起
It's not DNA.
沒有DNA
We stick with what we agreed. Finalise the evidence.
我們繼續按之前的計划 把証據確定下來
Eileen will come through for us,...
Eileen會讓我們安然度過的
Mr Foyle?
Foyle先生?
We had dinner together. She'll confirm that under oath. So the boot's not a problem?
我們一起吃的晚餐 她會在宣誓之下証明的 所以那雙靴子沒問題嗎
Not from where I'm sitting.
就我而言沒問題
Just him and what he says he saw.
只有他 和他聲稱自己所見
As it stands, yes.
目前來看是的
As it stands.
目前來看
You sure you're up for this?
你確定准備好了嗎
Right.
好的
Shall we start in here?
從這里開始嗎
Hey, come here.
嘿 過來
It's all right. It's all right.
沒事的 沒事
It's OK.
會好的
- Dad? - Yeah.
- 爸爸 - 怎么了
??????
我可以把書在eBay上賣嗎
You can do whatever you want with them.
隨你怎么處置
I might do the same myself.
我也許也會這么做
You? On eBay? You're rubbish with computers.
你?用eBay?你是電腦小白
Yes. Me. What?
我就要賣 咋了
There's no way. No way.
不可能 絕對不可能
You can't even turn a computer on.
你連開電腦都不會
I mean, I would eat my hat.
你要是會 我就把帽子吞下去
And I don't even have a hat.
我連帽子也沒有
Dad?
爸爸?
Mum said it was a surprise.
媽媽說有驚喜
A nice surprise.
愉快的驚喜
Speed-dial five, would you, please?
幫我快速撥號5
- What's going on? - I need to speak to someone, then we'll come back.
- 怎么了 - 我得找個人 一會兒就回來
Ready to dial?
撥好了嗎
- ???Can we go back now? - Press five on that phone and hold it down.
- 不能現在回去嗎 - 按住手機上的鍵盤5不放
- "Hello." - When were you planning on telling me?!
- 你好 - 你打算什么時候告訴我
- "Will?" - When he was in jail?
- Will? - 等他進監獄?
- "Listen..." - Never?
- 聽著 - 這輩子不告訴我?
Were you just going to send me an ultrasound in the post?
你打算在尸檢報告里 通知我B超結果嗎
"Are you driving?" I want a meeting with everyone tonight. You, Gavin, the coroner.
- 你在開車嗎 - 我要見所有人 你 Gavin 驗尸官
- Everyone!Hang up. - "Listen to me."
- 所有人 挂掉 - 聽我說
Sorry, Jamie.
抱歉 Jamie
Jamie?
Jamie?
I should have fought him harder.
我要是更奮力反抗就好了
It's my fault. I'm sorry.
都是我的錯 對不起
I should've tried again.
我應該再試試的
Jamie, what are you saying?
Jamie 你在說什么
I scratched his head.
我抓了他的頭
You scratched him with your hands?!
你用手抓了他的頭?
- And then I hid. - You were in a box by the door.
- 然后我躲起來了 - 你當時在門口的箱子里
Not the first time.
一開始不是
- You moved?! - Dad, look out!
- 你移動過了? - 爸爸 小心
I'm sorry.
對不起
Me too.
我也是
I just need you to take a nice deep breath, OK?
深呼吸
And now I want you to explain to me exactly what happened.
然后告訴我到底發生了什么
- Yep.- "Maggie, Peter. Forensic team just found DNA at the cottage."
- 喂 - Maggie 我是Peter 法醫在度假屋發現了DNA
- Foyle's? - "Mmm. The boy moved, they found a sample under the sink."
- Foyle的? - 嗯 那孩子移動過 他們在水斗下發現了樣本
Get on the phone and get Maggie!
打電話叫Maggie來
I want my legal team, not you, Simpkins!
我要我的法律團隊 不是你 Simpkins
You're driving me up the wall. I can't hear you speak anymore!
你要把我逼瘋了 我不想再聽你說話
"DNA it is, Mr Foyle. It's DNA!" What does DNA mean?!
"那是DNA Foyle先生 是DNA啊" DNA是什么鬼東西
Get Maggie here now!
讓Maggie過來 馬上
"15th Floor. Doors opening."
15樓到了
What kind of DNA is the DNA that we've got?!
找到的DNA是什么DNA
Where did this DNA come from, Mr Simpkins!
哪里來的DNA Simpkins先生
"I can't tell you, Mr Foyle."Is it from hair, Mr Simpkins? Is it from semen?!
"無可奉告 Foyle先生" 是頭發嗎 Simpkins先生 還是精液
You've locked him in?
你把他鎖里面了?
He said he'll only speak with you.
他說他只跟你說話
- You've locked him in? - Correct.
- 你把他鎖里面了? - 正確
We were discussing his alibi. Then the conversation drifted to the new DNA evidence.
我們之前在討論他的不在場証明 然后談話轉向了新的DNA証據
And you let it?
你也不回避?
It's only a low sample. Manifestly unreliable if we do our job properly.
只是低劑量樣本 很顯然 只要我們稍加辯論 就能証明不可靠
- He's not going to see it that way, is he? - I suppose not.
- 他可不這么看 不是嗎 - 恐怕不是
It puts me there.
這表明我去過了那里
- You're concerned about the DNA. - It puts me in that cottage.
- 你在擔心DNA - 表明我去過了度假屋
It puts me "at the locus", Margaret.
去過了"現場" Margaret
And now they think it's me.
現在他們覺得是我干的
They might think it says you were in the cottage...
他們也許會認為你去過別墅
Is this how it's going to be?
會這樣嗎
Here on in.
此后
Do you think I enjoy spending my life sitting in an airless room with his coffee breath?
你以為我喜歡一輩子呆在 密不透風的房間里 聞他的口臭?
It's like an infernal machine. It chews you up.
就像定時炸彈 讓人緊張不安
Doesn't speak. Doesn't listen. Just keeps moving forward.
不會說話 不會聽 只會不停向前
There's nothing you can do!
你什么也做不了
OK,
好了
- we need to back up for moment. - We?
- 我們得暫時倒退 - 我們?
We have a very clear alibi.
我們有清晰的不在場証明
We?
我們?
You love it, don't you. "We".
你喜歡這么說 是嗎 "我們"
We are one and the same.
你我是一體的
In terms of this trial, our fates are intertwined.
在這次庭審里 我們在同一條船上
But "we" don't go to prison. Do we?
但"我們"不會進監獄 是嗎
We were not in the cottage.
我們不在度假屋
No,... we... weren't.
是的 我們不在
So, we need to work out why the DNA would say that.
所以我們得弄清楚 為什么DNA會在那里
But it's science. And you can't argue with science.
但那是科學 你駁不倒科學
I can, Mr Foyle.
我可以 Foyle先生
In fact,
事實上
I can be very persuasive.
我很有說服力
Good.
很好
Be upstanding in court.
全體起立
Mr Burton, I know this is going to be hard for you given the circumstances, so please take your time.
Burton先生 考慮到現在的狀況 我知道這對您來說很痛苦 所以請慢慢來
I saw him through the window.
我透過窗子看到了他
Him being?
他是?
Liam Foyle.
Liam Foyle
He was known to you?
你認識他?
Yes. I'd just defended him in a criminal trial.
是的 我在一樁刑事審判中為他辯護
How often would you say you saw him during that period?
那段時間您多久見他一次
Almost daily.
六個月的審判期里
Over the trial period, six months.
几乎每天
Is there any doubt in your mind whatsoever
您是否懷疑過
that the man you saw during those times was the same man you saw staring at you through the kitchen window?
您在那段時間每天見的人 不是您透過廚房窗戶看到的人?
None whatsoever.
毫不懷疑
Ms Gardiner?
Gardiner女士?
Mr Burton, you are a practising criminal defence barrister, are you not?
Burton先生 您是職業刑事辯護律師 是嗎
Yes.
是的
If a situation arises where a case against an accused
如果一起案件對被告的定罪
depends to a great extent on the identification of the accused,
很大程度上依賴于對被告的身份鑒別
is there a warning the judge should give the jury?
在這種情況下 法官是否該給予陪審團警告?
Yes.
是的
- What is that warning called? - It's called a Turnbull Direction.
- 這種警告叫什么? - Turnbull指導
In your professional opinion,
根據你的專業觀點
is it important for the judge to warn the jury of the need for caution
如果案件中如此依賴目擊証人辨認
before convicting anyone in any case that relies so heavily on eyewitness identification?
那在定罪前 法官提醒陪審團慎重判斷 這一點是否重要
Yes.
是的
Should the judge, in that situation, ask the jury to closely examine
在這種情況下 法官是否應該 要求陪審團仔細檢視
every circumstance in which the identification was made?
目擊証人辨認的環境?
- Yes.I can list them for you if you like. - Would...
- 是的 我可以給你列舉 - 是...
No, thank you, I'm more than capable of recalling them on my own.
不必了 謝謝 我自己完全可以記起來
When you found her body, who did you see in the window?
你找到她的尸體時 看到誰在窗戶外?
I saw Liam Foyle.
Liam Foyle
- You had "no doubt whatsoever" it was him. - Yes.
- 你"毫不懷疑"是他 - 是的
There was a second individual present at the time Kate Burton was killed, wasn't there?
Kate Burton被殺時 現場還有另外一個人是 是嗎
Mr Burton?
Burton先生?
Yes.
是的
This would be your son James, is that right?
是你的兒子James 是嗎
According to his statement, he was unable to make "any identification
根據他的口供 他完全無法
of the attacker whatsoever." Is that right?
"辨認出襲擊者" 是嗎
He's nine years old. He was hiding in a box.
他才九歲 他當時躲在箱子里
So if I might ask again.
請允許我再確認一遍
Is it your understanding that he was not able to identify the attacker?
你是否認同 他無法辨認出襲擊者?
Yes.
是的
So 50 percent of persons present were not able to give a positive identification of the attacker.
所有現場50%的人 無法確認襲擊者的身份
Mr Burton, when a jury convicts, is it beyond all doubt? Is... Is that the term?
Burton先生 當陪審團定罪時 是否要確鑿無誤?那個朮語怎么說來著
- Reasonable doubt. - Beyond reasonable doubt.
- 合理的懷疑 - 排除合理懷疑
Now let's have a think about what might be reasonable in this situation, shall we?
那么 讓我們看看此案中 有哪些合理懷疑
- When you saw the man you are alleging was the accused, Mr Foyle, was it dark? - Yes.
- 當您見到您指認的被告Foyle先生時 是否天黑 - 是的
- Were you under stress? - Is that a serious question?
- 您當時壓力大嗎 - 你是認真的嗎
She was pregnant, did you know that?
她懷孕了 你知道嗎
Mr Burton.
Burton先生
- My Lord. - Part Seven, Code of Conduct.
- 法官大人 - 行為准則第七部分
Please try and remember that you are a witness and not counsel in this case, Mr Burton.
請記住你在此案中是目擊証人 不是律師 Burton先生
I am fully aware of the tragic circumstances we have surrounding us
我充分意識到此案中的慘境
and I am keenly aware of Mr Burton's incomprehensible loss, but in the case we have before us,
我也敏銳地意識到Burton先生 失去親人的痛苦 但這起案子中
Mr Burton's distress cannot be avoided if my client is to be givena fair trial.
如果要對我的委托人公正審判 那就無法避免觸及Burton先生的痛苦
Very well then.
好吧
When you saw the man in the garden, were you under stress in any way?
當你在花園里看到他時 你是否受到任何形式的精神壓力?
Yes.
是的
What is a Bar Standards complaint?
什么是律師標准委員會投訴
It's a formal letter listing a complaint against a practising barrister.
是針對一名執業律師的正式投訴信
Have you ever received such a complaint?
您是否收到過此種投訴?
I have.
收到過
Can you tell us who wrote that complaint?
能告訴我們是誰寫的投訴信嗎
- A former client of mine wrote it. - His name, please?
- 我的以前的一位委托人 - 請告訴我們他的名字
Liam Foyle.
Liam Foyle
In a dark room, in the shock and trauma of finding your wife in a pool of blood on the floor,
在一間昏暗的房間里 目睹妻子倒在血泊中 你當時處于極大的痛苦及震驚中
holding her in your arms, still unclear as to where your son was,
你把她抱在懷中 兒子仍舊下落不明
you look up at the window and you see a man,
你抬起頭 透過窗戶 看到一個人
a man who recently had been given cause to make a serious complaint
這個人最近向律師標准委員會
against your conduct to the Bar Standards Board,
投訴你行為
a man whose absence from your life would be very useful indeed.
如果沒有他 你的生活會很平靜
But it wasn't that man, was it, Mr Burton?
但不是這個人 是嗎 Burton先生?
You just wanted it to be.
只是你希望是他而已
- ????Stop her. - A bit late for that.
- 你得阻止她 - 太晚了
- She's twisting the facts to make them wrong. - Doing a good job of it too.
- 她在扭曲事實 - 而且干得漂亮
If Defence had a problem, they should've argued it at the time.
如果辯方有疑問 應及時提出
The issue has just come to light.
這個問題剛浮出水面
There's compelling evidence!
這是強有力的証據
Can I come round tonight, please? I'm freaking out.
我今晚能過來嗎 我嚇壞了
How did he know? There's no way he could have known.
他怎么會知道 他不可能知道的
When you killed her, did she die quickly?
你殺她時 她受到痛苦嗎
How do you live with yourself?
你良心怎么過的去?
You had us all worried for a minute.
你害所有人擔心了好一會兒
I'm just full of surprises.
我可是驚喜不斷
Join our FRS/FRM and have fun! QQ Group No. 77207643/frzhaopin2@gmail.com
時間軸招聘群號：77207643 翻譯組招聘郵箱：frzhaopin2@gmail.com 與最新美劇親密接觸 享受海量FTP下載
welcome to www.1000fr.net
風軟FRM字幕組作品 -==http://www.1000fr.net==- 歡迎加入